https://www.polypipe.com/privacy-cookies-policy

Skip to main content
close Change your regionPolypipe Polypipe International Polypipe Middle East Polypipe France CloseSearchSearch All products & Solutions Products & Systems Above Ground Drainage Below Ground Drainage Cable Protection Cavity Closers Commercial Ventilation Domestic Ventilation Effast Pressure Systems Plastic Plumbing View all Applications Sewer Systems Surface Water Drainage Terrain Drainage Underfloor Heating Water Management Solutions Sectors Building Services Civils & Green Urbanisation Homeowner & Self-Build Housing Product Literature & Technical InformationBrowse the literature library to find all product related literature including technical information, specification documents, datasheets, installation guides and much more.Browse Literature Library > Housing Above Ground Drainage Above Ground Drainage Products & Systems Rainwater Soil Spares & Ancillaries Traps Waste Applications Domestic Houses High Rise Residential Commercial Residential Above Ground Drainage Solutions Simple Push Fit Joints Extra Secure Welded Joints Below Ground Drainage Below Ground Drainage Products & Systems Civils Drainage Geothermal Systems Miscellaneous Pre-Insulated Pipes Utilities Water Supply Applications Domestic Drainage Systems Adoptable Sewer Systems Agricultural Drainage Systems Below Ground Drainage Solutions Inspection Chambers All Chambers Deep Inspection Chambers Chambers for Building Regulations Chambers for Sewers for Adoption Non Matching Drain and Sewer Connections The Benefits of Plastic Domestic Plumbing Systems Plumbing Fittings PolyFit - Hoses PolyFit - White Hand Demountable PolyMax - White, slim, sleek, attractive PolyPlumb - Grey Non-Demountable Fittings PolySure - Press Fit Fittings Plumbing & Heating Pipes Conduit Pipe Grey Barrier Pipe Pipe-in-Pipe PolyPlumb Pipe White Barrier Pipe Plumbing & Heating Solutions The Benefits of Plastic Tamper Proof Solutions Secure but Releasable Fittings Reducing Site Hot Works Reducing Theft from Site Extra Secure Joints Underfloor Heating Underfloor Heating Systems Existing Floors & Low Profile Systems Floating Floor Systems Solid Floor Systems Suspended Floor Systems Underfloor Heating Pipe & Accessories Underfloor Heating Manifolds & Controls Manifolds & Water Temperature Controls Room Temperature Controls Underfloor Heating Room Packs Overlay™ Room Packs Overlay™ Lite Room Packs Staple System Room Packs Panel System Room Packs Social Commercial Building Services Terrain Drainage Products & Systems Terrain PVC Soil & Waste Terrain dB12 Terrain FUZE Terrain Firetraps Terrain P.A.P.A. & Pleura Vent System Terrain Rainwater Outlets Siphonic Drainage Systems Terrain Underground Drainage Applications In-Building Rainwater & Rainwater Outlets In-Building Soil, Waste & Vent Chemical Soil & Waste Noise Reducing Soil & Waste Gravity Rainwater Gutter & Downpipes Underground Drainage Fire Compartmentalisation Solutions Polypipe Advantage Service Stack Replacement for Buildings in Use Noise Sensitive Environments Drainage in Tall Buildings Containment & Control of Thermal Movement Soil Stack Design Terrain Revit Families Terrain Technical Bulletins Water Supply Ventilation Water Management Solutions Pressure Systems Civils & Green Urbanisation Water Management Solutions Products & Systems Permavoid Geocellular System Polystorm Geocellular System Ridgistorm-XL Pipe System Ridgistorm Chambers Rainstream RXL - Rainwater Re-use Rainwater Interception System Rainstream Water Storage & Re-use System TreeBox HP ArborRaft Tree Root Development ArborRaft Tree Root Protection Infraweb Tree Root Protection SlimBlock FlowBlock Permavoid Sports Applications Green Infrastructure Surface Water Management Flood Alleviation Solutions Rainwater Harvesting & Water Re-Use Source Control Surface Water Solutions Water Storage For Evaporative Cooling Rainwater Interception, Storage & Control Difficult Geometries & Ground Conditions Reduce the Use of Potable Water Cellular Confinement Permeable Paving Surface Water Drainage Products & Systems Ridgidrain Pipe System Ridgistorm-XL Pipe System Ridgigully, Midigully & Ridgiflex Linflex Fin and Narrow Drains Landcoil Ridgitreat Treatment Pipes Ridgitrack Pipes Ridgistorm Chambers Ridgidrain Inspection Chambers Applications Highway Drainage Rail Drainage Land Drainage Commercial & Public Drainage Port & Harbour Drainage Solutions Surface Water Drainage Drainage Access and Maintenance Surface Water Treatment Sewer Systems Products & Systems Polysewer 150-300mm Pipes Ridgisewer 400-900mm Pipes Ridgistorm-XL Pipe System Polysewer Inspection Chambers RIDGISTORMAccess Manholes Applications Adoptable Sewers Solutions Drainage Access and Maintenance Cable Protection Products & Systems Ridgiduct Polyduct Ridgicoil PVCu Cable TV Duct Access and Pole Boxes, Covers and Frames Cable Guard PVCu Specification and Utility Duct Hockey Sticks Comtite Duct Plugs UTX Chambers General Purpose Duct Applications Power Lighting Motorway Comms Utilities Solutions Homeowner & self build Underfloor Heating Elegance Colour Home Homeowner Explore the Collection 4 Steps to Elegance Technical Information Request a Sample FAQs Why Polypipe? Request an Estimate Contact Architect Explore the Collection Choosing a System Technical Information Request your Sample FAQs Why Polypipe? Request an Estimate ContactHomePrivacy & Cookies Policy Privacy & Cookies Policy
The website www.polypipe.com is operated by Polypipe Limited a limited liability company incorporated in England and Wales under company number 1099323, of Broomhouse Lane, Edlington, Doncaster, South Yorkshire, UK, DN12 1ES  ("we", "us", "our" or "Polypipe") and we are a "data controller" for the purposes of the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (GDPR).  This means that we are responsible for, and control the processing of, your personal information.  Polypipe Limited, its trading divisions and all Polypipe Group companies are committed to protecting and respecting your data and your privacy. This Privacy and Cookies Policy (together with our [Data Protection Policy], Terms of Use, Trading Terms and any other documents referred to within them) ("Policy") sets out the basis on which any Personal Data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, or will be processed by us and the purpose for our collection of it. Please read the following carefully to understand our practices regarding your Personal Data and how we will treat it. The Policy outlines:How we will adhere to the principles relating to processing of Personal Data set out in the GDPRHow any data collected or provided by you will be processed lawfully, fairly and in a transparent mannerOn what lawful basis we will rely to process your data, as set out in the GDPROur commitment to ensuring that Personal Data will be kept accurate and stored only for the period which it is required to complete its purposeOur commitment that Personal Data will be securely stored and protectedThe rights Data Subjects have when it comes to how we handle their Personal DataOur accountabilities and responsibilities, as a Data Controller Our principles for processing Personal Data As outlined in the GDPR and the Policy, we will:Process data lawfully, fairly and in a transparent manner (Lawfulness, Fairness and Transparency)Collect only for specified, explicit and legitimate purposes (Purpose Limitation)Collect only adequate, relevant and limited data proportionate to what is necessary for the purposes for which it is Processed (Data Minimisation).Keep data accurate and where necessary up to date (Accuracy)Not keep data in a form which permits identification of Data Subjects for longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the data is Processed (Storage Limitation)Process data in a manner that ensures its security using appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect against unauthorised or unlawful Processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage (Security, Integrity and Confidentiality)Not transfer to another country without appropriate safeguards being in place (Transfer Limitation)Make data available to Data Subjects and Data Subjects allowed to exercise certain rights in relation to their Personal Data (Data Subject’s Rights and Requests)Be responsible for and comply with the data protection principles listed above (Accountability) What Personal Data do we collect and why do we collect it?We may collect and process Personal Data about you including information you have:Provided by filling in forms on our websitesProvided by registering user accounts to our websitesProvided by filling in forms or handing us your details at exhibitionsCommunicated through email or other electronic meansCommunicated during certain telephone calls to and from us, if further engagement is requiredSupplied in postal or hardcopy correspondenceProvided to us to allow customer or supplier transactions and business relationshipsSupplied to us to allow a non-transactional business activity to be conductedProvided to us as part of a job application or student placement applicationSupplied as part of consenting to opt into our marketing communicationsOffered as part of being an investorOffered as part of being an employee We may also collect Personal Data and other information about you in other ways, for example:If you are a customer of one of our clients, and we are undertaking a business activity that involves you i.e. we are creating a technical design for your construction projectIndirectly, through one of our employees, your colleagues, a client or a third partyFrom publicly available sources, for example Companies House, trade mediaFrom financial parties, for example credit check providers How we use your Personal DataThe way we process the Personal Data we collect as set out above, varies depending on our relationship with you. In each case the purposes for which we request the information will be clear from the context in which it is acquired. These may include:Processing and fulfilling a business service or transactionKeeping a record of the business service, transaction or other related customer service support activityAdministering customer and supplier records for transactional purposesKeeping records of your subscriptions, registrations, queries, complaints and deliveriesKeeping records of face-to-face appointments, with outcomesVerifying your identity through credit checksVerifying your identity through an automated double-opt in processCommunicating for business or service reasons by mobile (SMS), telephone, email, fax or post (non-marketing communications)Communicating marketing messages to you, based on lawful consent as set out in the GDPR, by mobile (SMS), telephone, email, fax or postCommunicating tailored marketing messages to you, based on lawful consent as set out in the GDPR, that are relevant to your role, marketing preferences and website behaviours - upon receipt and engagement with automated email marketing – note your profile on automated decision making from an email is not identifiable to an individualKeeping a record of any withdrawn consent to receive marketing communications from usFor market researchActivity to meet our legal, regulatory and contractual obligations arising from our relationship with youTo administer our e-commerce websites and enhance our servicesTo administer services provided through our websitesBy verifying or enforcing compliance with this Privacy Policy and applicable lawsBy informing you of legal or contractual changes that may affect youFor recruitment purposes, if necessary Disclosure of your Personal DataWe will only disclose your Personal Data to another person or organisation where we:Are required to disclose the information to comply with the law or the requirements of a regulatory authorityNeed to transfer your data between Polypipe companiesAre compelled to share the information to provide a product or service you have requestedAre obligated to send the information to persons or organisations who conduct legal services on our behalfEmploy GDPR compliant external contractors to undertake marketing activities on our behalf Our legal basis for using your Personal DataOur use of your Personal Data as outlined above is subject to different legal basis for processing, including where necessary for:Compliance with our legal and regulatory responsibilitiesThe purposes of fulfilling any contract we enter with youCarrying out a service request or transactionTo protect your vital interestsPursuing our legitimate interests for purposes where they are not overridden because the Processing prejudices the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of Data Subjects. In such cases, these may include:Communicating marketing messages to transactional customersCommunicating marketing messages to customers we enter a contract with or supply or perform a service forCommunicating with third-party marketing service providers that are GDPR compliant and their compliance to our GDPR policy annually verifiedCommunicating with recipients who have legally consented with a third-party to receive updates relating to their sector or role. Such third-parties will be GDPR compliant and their compliance to our GDPR policy annually verifiedOr where you have given clear consentWe will only use your data for the purposes outlined above and will not store any of your data which is unrelated to our legal basis for processing it. Withdrawing consent or your right to refuse:Where we ask for your consent to provide us with your Personal Data, you are free to refuse and withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us using the details set out below. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, we will require your email address only to ensure we stop any automated marketing communications. This shall not affect the lawfulness of any processing that was based on your consent before you withdrew it.If you do not agree to provide your Personal Data to us we may not be able to provide you with the transaction or service you require. Our principles of using your data for marketingWhere processing your data for marketing purposes in compliance with GDPR, we will adhere to the following principles to ensure our commitment to protecting your data is clear:We will not sell your data to any third-party companyWe will safely and securely share data between Polypipe companies through a single platformIf you opt in to a Polypipe marketing database, you will have the option to confirm how you would like to hear from us. For example, through all mechanisms, or selectively via email, SMS, telephone and/or mail. You can also choose which Polypipe business you would like to opt in toWe will check our marketing database for accuracy and compliance on an ongoing basisIf we have not heard from you within 12 months, we will remind you of your option to withdraw from our marketing communicationsYou can opt-out of any Polypipe business you have consented to receive marketing updates from, through a single requestPolypipe will use a single, secure and trusted platform, for all automated marketing communicationsWithin this platform we will keep the email record of anyone opting out of marketing communications, to ensure compliance, on an on-going basis. This will not prevent you from opting-back in at any pointAll telephone marketing campaigns will be checked against the Telephone Preference Service (TPS) and Corporate Telephone Preference Service CTPS as well as our own suppression database before commencing Personal Data we may collect, to ensure our marketing communications are relevant to you:Name,TitleJob titleJob function or role for example PurchaserGenderCompany nameCompany typeWork address (unless you specify other)Work telephone number (unless you specify other)Working mobile number (unless you specify other)Work fax number (unless you specify other)Work email address (unless you specify other)Marketing preferences, Source of data e.g. webform, exhibitionPolypipe purchase history, by productDetails of any current/upcoming projectsIf gained through a competition, details relating to said competitionDate obtained at event if applicable Recruitment It may be necessary to for us to obtain data from prospective employees, in-order to monitor and evaluate our recruitment practices and ensure they remain legally compliant with equal opportunity legislation. Mechanisms for data collection may include on and off-line.Personal Data we may collect, as part of our recruitment and graduate programmes which may include:NameTitleEducation historyContact telephone numberContact addressGenderEthnic groupDisabilities Storage and transfer of your Personal Data outside of the UK and EU (Economic European Area -EEA)We will only transfer Personal Data outside the EEA if one of the following conditions applies:The European Commission issues a decision confirming that the country to which we may wish to transfer your Personal Data ensures an adequate level of protection of your rights and freedoms, as the Data SubjectYou have provided explicit consent to the proposed transfer after being informed of any potential risks; orThe transfer is necessary for one of the following reasons set out in the GDPR including:The performance of a contract between you and PolypipeReasons of public interest, to establish, exercise or defend legal claimsTo protect your vital interests, if you were to be physically or legally incapable of giving consent and, in some limited cases, for our legitimate interestAppropriate safeguards are in place such as binding corporate rules (BCR), standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission, an approved code of conduct or a certification mechanism, a copy of which can be obtained from usPolypipe have put in place an Intra-Group Data Sharing Agreement which we would comply with always when transferring Personal Data between group Companies Retention of your Personal DataWe will retain your personal information for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purpose for which it was obtained and in accordance with our legal obligations. We will also ensure that we follow our data retention and destruction policy and processes thereafter. For more information about our retention period please contact our Company Secretary on 01702 772 778. Links to other websitesThis Policy only extends to our websites, which are owned and operated by Polypipe Limited and does not therefore extend to your use of, provision of information to the collection of information on any website not connected to Polypipe, which you may link to us, by using the hypertext links within our website; or from other websites back-linking to our website. Your rightsYour personal information is protected under GDPR and you have several rights, as listed below, which you can seek to implement. Please contact us in writing, by email or telephone using the details shown under the ‘Contact and Complaints’ section below if you wish to do so, or if you have any queries in relation to your rights. Please note these rights do not apply in all circumstances.Right of access – subject to certain exceptions, you have the right of access to your Personal Data that we holdRight to rectify your personal information – if you identify that the information we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you have the right to have this information rectified (i.e. corrected)Right to withdraw consent – you may ask us to delete information we hold about you in certain circumstances. This right is not absolute and it may not be possible for us to delete the information we hold about you, for example, if we have an ongoing contractual relationship or are required to retain information to comply with our legal obligationsRight to restriction of processing i.e. for marketing purposes or automated profiling – in some cases you may have the right to have the processing of your personal information restricted. For example, where you contest the accuracy of your personal information, its use may be restricted until the accuracy is verifiedRight to object to processing – you may object to the processing of your personal information (including profiling) when it is based upon our legitimate interests. You may also object to the processing of your personal information for the purposes of direct marketing and for the purposes of analysisRight to data portability – you have the right to receive, move, copy or transfer your personal information to another controller when we are processing your personal information based on consent or on a contract and the processing is carried out by automated meansRight to know how we process your data – the right to be told how we process your dataRight to challenge - the ability to challenge the processing of your dataRight to request EEA agreements – you can request a copy of our agreement under which Personal Data may be transferred outside of the EEARight to prevent damage or distress - the choice to stop data processing that is likely to cause damage or distress to the Data Subject or anyone elseRight to be notified of a breach – we have the obligation and you have the right to be notified of a Personal Data Breach which is likely to result in high risk to your rights and freedomsRight to make a complaint – you can make a complaint to the supervisory authority and in limited circumstances, receive or ask for your Personal Data to be transferred to a third party in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. The Supervisory Authority for the United Kingdom is the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO) who can be contacted at https://ico.org.uk/ or by calling them on 0303 123 1113. IP addressesWe may collect information about your device, including where available, your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to collect aggregate information for us to use to improve our websites. This is statistical data about our users’ browsing actions and patterns and does not identify any individual. CookiesWhat are cookies and why do we use them?Cookies are small text files that are created and stored on your browser or the hard drive of your device by websites that you visit to enable the website to proactively operate and ‘remember’ who you are. They are also used to monitor website traffic. Cookies are generally only visible to the website that serves them and not to other websites.Our cookies are used on our website to ‘remember’ information so that it can be passed from page to page and to collect website statistics. This statistical data may be used to help improve our websites, offers and the services that we offer to you. Some of our cookies will also recognise you as a previous visitor the next time you visit our websites to improve your experience – if you have consented to be remembered. Cookie types explained:There are two types of Cookie;Session Cookies - These cookie files are erased when you close your browser. This cookie stores your browsing information and will be active until you leave a site and close your browser.Persistent Cookies - These files stay in one of a browser's subfolder until they are deleted manually or your browser deletes them based on the duration period contained within the persistent cookie's file. You can set your browser to automatically remove these cookies on logging off. Our use of cookiesAt Polypipe we specifically use cookies for:Social SharingEnabling you to share Polypipe stories and page content via social media components, like Facebook and Twitter.AnalyticsWe like to anonymously keep track of user behaviour to help us keep our website content relevant and up to date. It's also useful to identify trends of how people navigate through our websites. How to manage cookiesMost internet browsers accept cookies automatically however, you can accept, delete or disable cookies if you wish; the process for which can usually be found in your internet browser’s ‘Help’ menu.If you don’t want these cookies to be used when visiting a Polypipe website, you can remove them by following these simple steps:1. Click Tools & select Internet Options2. Click the Privacy tab, and select Advanced3. Click Override automatic cookie handling4. Specify how you wish to handle cookies from first-party Websites and third-party WebsitesFor more information about cookies and instructions on how to adjust your browsers settings to accept, delete or reject cookies, see the IAB website. The relevant page for adjusting your browser settings is available here.If you disable cookies then, whilst you may be able to browse all our websites, some of the cookies we use may be essential for the operation and features we offer and therefore may not be available to you. Unless you have adjusted your browser settings so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies as soon as you visit our websites. SecurityPolypipe Limited takes great care to ensure the security of our platforms, including websites and your personal information is kept secure and safe. Only authorised personnel have access to your information. We will keep your information secure by taking appropriate technical and organisational measures against unauthorised or unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction and damage. Changes to this Privacy PolicyWe may change this Policy at any time by amending this page. You are expected to check this page from time to time to take notice of any changes we have made, as they are binding on you.  If we make any substantial changes in the way we use your Personal Data, we will notify you by posting a prominent notice on our websites. Contact usIf you have any questions about how we treat your Personal Data and protect your privacy, or if you have any comments or wish to seek to exercise any of your rights as outlined above, to opt-out of receiving marketing communications from us or to complain about our use of your Personal Data, please contact us at: Marketing & Development DirectorPolypipe LimitedBroomhouse LaneEdlingtonDoncasterUnited KingdomDN12 1ESTel: +44 (0)1709 770000Fax: +44 (0)1709 770001Available During Office HoursMon - Fri: 09:00 - 17:30 (GMT)Last updated: 17th May 2018
